In this video, I'm going to describe some of the things that make it difficult to
在这段视频中，我将介绍为什么计算机在 真实场景中识别物体是一件很困难的事情
recognize objects in real scenes. We're incredibly good at this, and so it's
这对我们人类来说轻而易举
very hard for us to realize how difficult it is to take a bunch of numbers that
所以我们很难意识到这有多困难
describe the intensities of pixels and go from there to the label of an object.
这需要我们将一大堆用来表示像素强度的 数据处理成物体的标签
There's all sorts of difficulties. We have to segment the object out.
这里边包括了各种各样的困难 我们需要将物体分割出来
We have to deal with variations in lighting, in viewpoint.
我们需要处理光线、观察点的变化
We have to deal with the fact that the definitions of objects are quite
我们需要处理物体的定义 这非常复杂
complicated. It's also possible that to get from an
还有一种可能性
image to an object requires huge amounts of knowledge, even for the lower level
从图像中识别物体需要大量的知识
processes that involve segmentation and dealing with viewpoint and lighting.
甚至包括图像分割、处理光线观察点等低级的过程
If that's the case, it's gonna be very hard for any hand engineered program to be
这样的话 手工设计能够很好地识别物体 的程序非常困难
able to do a good job of those things. There are many reasons why it's hard to
存在许多原因 导致了从图像中识别物体如此困难
recognize objects and images. First of all, it's hard to segment out an
首先 很难将一个物体与图像中的其他物体分割开来
object from the other things in an image. In the real world, we move around, and so
在现实世界中 我们四处移动 所以我们拥有运动感知
we have motion cues. We also have two eyes, so we have stereo
此外我们有两只眼睛 所以我们拥有立体感知
cues. You don't get those in static images.
这些你无法在静止的图像中得到
So it's very hard to tell which pieces go together as parts of the same object.
所以 很难判断图像中的哪些部分属于同一个物体
Also, parts of an object can be hidden behind other objects, and so, you often
除此之外 一个物体的部分可能被其他物体所遮挡
don't see the whole of an object. You're so good at doing vision that you
所以 你常常无法看到物体的全貌 你的视觉如此发达 以至于常常不会注意到这一点
don't often notice this. Another thing that makes it very hard to
另一个使得识别物体如此困难的原因是
recognize objects is that the intensity of a pixel is determined as much by the
一个像素点的强度同时取决于光线
lighting as it is by the nature of the object.
和它自身的属性
So, for example, a black surface in bright light will give you much more intense
举个例子 一个强光照射下的黑色表面和
pixels than a white surface in very gloomy light.
一个弱光下的白色表面具有相同的像素强度
Remember, to recognize an object you've got to convert a bunch of numbers, that is
要记住 识别一个物体就是 将一堆像素点的强度值
the intensities of the pixels, into a class label.
转换为一个物体种类的标签
And, these intensities are varying for all sorts of reasons that have nothing to do
这些像素强度值会出于各种各样的原因变化
with the nature of the object. Or nothing to do with the identity of the
这些原因往往与物体的自身属性无关 换句话说 与这个物体本身无关
object. Objects can also deform in a variety of
物体会发生各种不同形式的变形
ways. So for relatively simple things like
所以 相当简单的东西 比如手写数字
handwritten digits there's a wide variety of different shapes that have the same
叫着同一个名字 却有着截然不同的形状
name. A two for example could be very italic
一个数字 2 可以是意大利体的
with just a cusp instead of a loop or it could be a very loopy two with a, a big
转折处是一个尖端而非圆圈
loop and very round. It's also the case that for many types of
它也可以有一个非常大而圆的圈
object, the class is defined more by what the object's for, than by its visual
很多种物体都是这样 物体的类别往往不是由外形来定义
appearance. So consider chairs.
不妨考虑椅子
There's a huge variety of things we call chairs, from armchairs to modern chairs
有不少东西都叫做椅子 从老式扶手椅到休闲沙发
made with steel frames and wood backs to basically anything you can sit on.
从钢结构实木靠背的现代椅 到任何你可以坐上去的东西
One other thing that makes it hard to recognize objects, is that we have
另一个使得识别物体如此困难的原因 是观察点的不同
different viewpoints. So, there's a wide variety of viewpoints
识别一个三维物体的观察点可以在很大范围内变化
from which we can recognize a 3D object. Now, changes in viewpoint cause changes in
观察点的改变引起了图像的改变
the images that standard machine learning methods cannot cope with.
这使得标准机器学习算法难以处理
The problem is that information hops about between the input dimensions.
问题在于 信息在输入维度之间跳来跳去
So, typically envision the input dimensions correspond to pixels, and, if
设想一个典型情形 输入维数同像素点相对应
an object moves in the world and you don't move your eyes to follow it, the
如果一个现实世界中的物体在移动 而你的眼睛没有移动以跟住它
information about the object will occur on different pixels.
那么这个物体的信息会出现在不同的像素点上
That's not the kind of thing we normally have to deal with in machine learning.
这与我们在机器学习中处理的一般问题不同
Just to stress that point, suppose we had a medical database in which one of the
为了强调这一点 假设我们有一个医疗数据库
inputs is the age of a patient and another input is the weight of the patient.
一个输入是病人的年龄 另一个输入是病人的体重
And we start doing machine learning, and then we realize that some coder has
下面开始进行机器学习 我们发现
actually changed which input I mentioned is coding which property.
一些编码器更改了输入到属性的编码关系
So for one of the coders they've put weight where they should have put age, and
即对于编码器中的一个 他们在应该放年龄的地方放了体重
they put age where they should have put weight.
他们在应该放体重的地方放了年龄
Obviously, we wouldn't just carry on doing our learning.
显然 我们不能再继续我们的机器学习了
We'd try and do something to fix that. That's going to make everything go wrong.
我们应当尝试着修复这个问题 它会搞砸整个事情
I call that phenomenon dimension hopping. When information jumps from one input
我把这个现象叫做维度跳跃 信息从一个输入维度跳跃到了另一个
dimension to another. And that's what Viewpoint does and it's
这正是观察点变化所做的 也正是需要我们解决的
something we need to fix. And preferably we'd like to fix it in a
我们更希望以一系统化的方式解决这个问题
systematic way.
翻译 Haozhe Zhu